<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>backend on Hiep&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://duongphuhiep.github.io/categories/backend/</link>
    <description>Recent content in backend on Hiep&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 21:27:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://duongphuhiep.github.io/categories/backend/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>C# System.Text.Json</title>
      <link>https://duongphuhiep.github.io/posts/csharp-system-text-json/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 21:27:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duongphuhiep.github.io/posts/csharp-system-text-json/</guid>
      <description>There is many Json Serializer for .NET out there.
Microsoft used to depend on the Newtonsoft.Json (aka. Json.NET) library. Howerver, since the .NET Core 3, Microsoft introduced their own json serializer in the System.Text.Json package.
The Michael Blog&amp;rsquo;s post published some benchmark on differents .NET Json Serializers. His benchmark show that the new System.Text.Json of Microsoft is not the fastest one, but the speed favor appears to go to the jil serializer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Did I Build My Blog</title>
      <link>https://duongphuhiep.github.io/posts/how-did-i-build-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 20:52:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duongphuhiep.github.io/posts/how-did-i-build-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>None of the FREE blogging platforms fit my taste! As a fullstack developper it was a shame if I can&amp;rsquo;t built my own website..
Requirements for my Blog  No-cost (otherwise it is a shame for me!) Easy-to-read interface.  peoples with slight vision imperfections (eg. Color Vision Deficiency) should be able to read my blog wihout much effort.   Manage content (CRUD) should not complicate. I usually write text and codes snippets then Markdown is a no-brainer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# (or Java) Programming Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://duongphuhiep.github.io/posts/csharp-java-programming-some-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 14:21:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duongphuhiep.github.io/posts/csharp-java-programming-some-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Base on my years experiences in codes review, I recognized some best practices which is really simple to apply to sanitize the codes, make them more testable or reusable. Experienced developers might apply some of them and don&amp;rsquo;t even realize it.
In this article I will expose some of the common coding mistakes which I often see in codes review sessions along with some simple / best practice to avoid them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit Testing</title>
      <link>https://duongphuhiep.github.io/posts/unit-testing-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:06:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duongphuhiep.github.io/posts/unit-testing-en/</guid>
      <description>A long time ago, a certain CTO asked me to write unit tests for a legacy application in order to increase the Sonar rating.. I did all I could, and hardly covered up to 40% of the codes. My &amp;ldquo;unit tests&amp;rdquo; that I wrote can run only if the database was well configured with some specific data.. Many &amp;ldquo;unit tests&amp;rdquo; depend on the server of other teams..
At that moment I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize that the task was absurd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit Testing</title>
      <link>https://duongphuhiep.github.io/posts/unit-testing-vn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:35:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duongphuhiep.github.io/posts/unit-testing-vn/</guid>
      <description>Lúc mới vào nghề, có lần Sếp yêu cầu tôi viết Unit Test cho 1 ứng dụng cũ của công ty để tăng điểm Sonar. Sau nhiều cố gắng, các &amp;ldquo;Unit test&amp;rdquo; của tôi cũng chỉ phủ được khoảng 40% đám codes của ứng dụng cũ đó. Hơn nữa, muốn chạy được các &amp;ldquo;Unit test&amp;rdquo; đó, cần phải cấu hình CSDL, có dữ liệu mẫu và kết nối với các Ứng dụng ngoài (được phát triển bởi các nhóm khác)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>